Guide to the Bryan Gallery of Christian Art Print Collection circa 1525-circa 1870 PR 143
New-York Historical Society
Bryan Gallery of Christian Art print collection
circa 1525-circa 1870
New-York Historical Society
Bryan, Thomas Jefferson, 1800?-1870
PR 143
20 folder(s) in 2 drawers.
Prints, photographs, and one drawing, from the Bryan Gallery of Christian Art, assembled by Thomas Jefferson Bryan and given to the New-York Historical Society in 1867. All 158 prints are European works, mainly of religious subjects, but including some portraits, landscapes, and allegorical scenes. Portraits include some from a set of portraits of the six wives of Henry VIII, and several self-portraits, mainly by Italian artists. Artists represented include: David Teniers, Rubens, Van Dyck, Watteau, Dürer, Titian, Philips Wouwerman, Nicolas Lancret, Aelbert Cuyp, Holbein, and Guido Reni. Engravers represented include Francesco Bartolozzi, Schelte Bolswert, Cornelis Cort, Christoffel Jegher, Jacques-Philippe Le Bas, Jean Moyreau, William Sharp, Cornelis Vermeulen, and Lucas Emil Vorsterman. The prints include etchings, engravings, stipple engravings, and mezzotints. The albumen photographs show the Alhambra in Spain, and paintings in Perugia, Italy. The collection also contains one amateur crayon or pastel drawing, and two photomechanical reproductions (one in color) of engravings.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in three series:
Series I.
Prints, before 1528-1817, undated
Series II.
Photographs, undated
Series III.
Other items, undated
Items are sorted by the numbers they were assigned on accession.
Biographical note
Thomas Jefferson Bryan was the first major American collector and connoisseur of European paintings. He was born in Philadelphia in 1802. In 1852, after spending twenty years in Europe, he returned to New York and opened the Gallery of Christian Art, which he operated out of his residence on Broadway. As his collection grew, he sought a more permanent home for it, and arranged its transfer to the New-York Historical Society in 1867. Bryan continued to add to the collection until his death in 1870.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Thomas Jefferson Bryan, April 2, 1867. Bryan added material to the collection until his death in 1870.
Related Materials
Documentation related to the original Bryan collection and its acquisition by N-YHS can be found in the institutional archives; see Guide to the New-York Historical Society Bequests, Gifts and Related Matters Record Group.
Much of the Bryan collection was deaccessioned in the 1970s–1990s. For details on its scope, see Richard Grant White, Companion to the Bryan Gallery of Christian Art: Containing Critical Descriptions of the Pictures, and Biographical Sketches of the Painters (1853).
Scope and Contents
The Bryan Gallery of Christian Art Print Collection spans the period circa 1525–circa 1870 and primarily contains European prints. The collection is organized in three series: Prints, Photographs, and Other Items.
Series I. Prints, before 1528-1817, undated, contains 158 prints. All are European works, and include Italian, Flemish, French, Dutch, and some English works. Most of the prints are engravings or etchings, and only a few have color. They are mainly of religious subjects, or are portraits, landscapes, or allegorical scenes. Many of the portraits are self-portraits by artists, primarily Italian. Several others are from a set of portraits of the six wives of Henry VIII. Prints number nine and ten are both colored stipple prints from a set of illustrations for Milton's Paradise Lost engraved by Francesco Bartolozzi after Thomas Stotherd. Duplicate copies exist of a few prints.
Series II. Photographs, undated, contains two groups of albumen photographs showing paintings in Perugia, Italy, and the Alhambra in Spain. The seven photographs of the Alhambra are 8 by 10 inches. The twenty-three photographs of paintings are 5 x 7 inches and smaller.
Series III. Other items, undated, contains one amateur crayon or pastel drawing and two photomechanical reproductions, one in color, of engravings.
Alhambra (Granada, Spain) -- Photographs; Albumen prints.; Drawings (visual works); Engravings (prints); Etchings (prints); Mezzotints (prints); Photomechanical prints.; Stipple engravings (prints); Christian art and symbolism.; Prints -- Belgium -- 17th century.; Prints -- Belgium -- 18th century.; Prints -- Belgium -- 19th century; Prints -- England -- 17th century; Prints -- England -- 18th century; Prints -- England -- 19th century; Prints -- France -- 17th century; Prints -- France -- 18th century; Prints -- France -- 19th century; Prints -- Italy -- 17th century.; Prints -- Italy -- 18th century.; Prints -- Italy -- 19th century; Bartolozzi, Francesco, 1727-1815; Bolswert, Schelte, approximately 1586-1659; Cort, Cornelis, 1533?-1578; Cuyp, Aelbert, 1620-1691; Dürer, Albrecht, 1471-1528; Holbein, Hans, 1497-1543; Jegher, Christoffel, approximately 1596-1652 or 1653; Lancret, Nicolas, 1690-1743; Le Bas, Jacques-Philippe, 1707-1783; Moyreau, Jean, 1690-1762; Reni, Guido, 1575-1642; Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640; Sharp, William, 1749-1824; Teniers, David, 1610-1690; Titian, approximately 1488-1576; Van Dyck, Anthony, 1599-1641; Vermeulen, Cornelis, approximately 1644-approximately 1708; Vorsterman, Lucas Emil, 1595-1675; Watteau, Antoine, 1684-1721; Wouwerman, Philips, 1619?-1668; Bryan Gallery of Christian Art (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I. Prints, before 1528-1817, undated
  Arrangement
  The following inventory lists the 158 numbered prints in Series I. These numbers [in brackets] were assigned at the time of accession. Titles in quotes and attributions were transcribed from the prints. Brief descriptions were given for those prints without titles in the plate; these appear in brackets. Those prints in folders 16, 17, and 18 were exhibited, or were considered for exhibition, in 1990. Those in folders 17 and 18 are matted.
  - [001] "Depart Pour le Sabat," after David Teniers II (1610-1690), by Jacques Aliamet (1726-1788), undated (Folder 1)
  - [002] "Arrivee au Sabat," after David Teniers II (1610-1690), by Jacques Aliamet (1726-1788), undated (Folder 1)
  - [003] "Le Betail au Repos," after Jacob van Ruisdael (circa 1628-1682), by Jacques Bacheley (1712-1781), undated (Folder 16)
  - [004] "Christ in the Garden of Olives," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), drawn by Frans van den Wyngaerde (1614-1679), engraved by Pieter de Bailliu (1613-circa 1660), undated (Folder 17)
  - [005] [Portrait of royalty] after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), drawn by Johannes Meyssens (1612-1670), engraved by Peter de Baillie (1644-1726), undated (Folder 17)
  - [006] "Iacopo Bassano," after Jacopo Bassano (circa 1510-1592), drawn by Giovanni Sanguinetti (1789-1867), engraved by Giuseppe Barni, undated (Folder 1)
  - [007] "Donna Che Accorda le Liuto," after Cornelis Pietersz Bega (circa 1631-1664), drawn by Angiolo Tricca (1817-1884), engraved by Giuseppe Barni, undated (Folder 1)
  - [008] "A Concert" after Guercino (1591-1666), by Francesco Bartolozzi (1727-1815), 1758-64 (Folder 18)
  - [009] [Man with spear, illustration for Paradise Lost] after Thomas Stotherd (1755-1834), by Francesco Bartolozzi (1727-1815), 1793 (Folder 1)
  - [010] "Pandemonian, illustration for Paradise Lost" after Thomas Stotherd (1755-1834), by Francesco Bartolozzi (1727-1815), 1792 (Folder 1)
  - [011] "La Game d'Amour," after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721), by Jacques Philippe Le Bas (1707-1783), 1726-29 (Folder 17)
  - [012] [Raphael painting Mary and Jesus] after Cornelis Bloemaert (1603-circa 1684), engraved by Giovanni Jacopo de Rubeis (working 1649-1680), undated (Folder 1)
  - [013] "The Last Supper," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Schelte Bolswert (1586-1659), undated (Folder 2)
  - [014] "Johannes Bercmans," by Boetius Bolswert (1580-1633), undated (Folder 2)
  - [015] "Saint Barbara," by Schelte Bolswert (1586-1659), undated (Folder 16)
  - [016] [Shepherds] after Hans Jordaens (circa 1572-1630), by Schelte Bolswert (1586-1659), undated (Folder 13)
  - [017] [Mary and Jesus] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Schelte Bolswert (1586-1659), undated (Folder 2)
  - [018] [Old woman and child with angels] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Schelte Bolswert (1586-1659), undated (Folder 2)
  - [019] "Adrianus Brouwer," after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), by Schelte Bolswert (1586-1659), undated (Folder 16)
  - [020] [Christ carrying cross], undated (Folder 2)
  - [021] "Flight into Egypt," after Titian (circa 1488-1576), by Guilio Bonasone (working 1531-1574), undated (Folder 2)
  - [022] "Thomas Paine," by Francois Bonneville (working 1787), [circa 1787] (Folder 2)
  - [023] "Laure Petrarque," after Simone Martini (1284-1344), by Francoise-Eugin-Augustin Bridoux (1813-1892), 1842 (Folder 13)
  - [024] [Cattle and village scene] after Pieter van Laer (1599-1642), by Pierre-Charles Canot (1710-1777), 1769 (Folder 3)
  - [025] [Cattle and horses in village] after Pieter van Laer (1599-1642), by Pierre-Charles Canot (1710-1777), 176[?] (Folder 3)
  - [026] "S. Catarina," after Agostino Carracci (1557-1602), undated (Folder 3)
  - [027] "Tyberio Delphino," after Agostino Carracci (1557-1602), undated (Folder 3)
  - [028] [Susannah and the Elders] after Aniballe Carracci (1560-1609), undated (Folder 16)
  - [029] [Holy Family] by L. Carario, 1604? (Folder 3)
  - [030] [Annunciation] after Titian (circa 1488-1576), by Giovanni-Jacopo Caraglio (circa 1500-1570), undated (Folder 3)
  - [031, copy 1] [The blind man duped] after Jean-Baptiste Greuze (1725-1805), by Laurent Cars (1699-1771), undated (Folder 4)
  - [031, copy 2] [The blind man duped] after Jean-Baptiste Greuze (1725-1805), by Laurent Cars (1699-1771), undated (Folder 18)
  - [032] "La Diseuse Daventure," after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721) by Laurent Cars (1699-1771), undated (Folder 4)
  - [033] "St. John the Baptist Penitent," after Giovanni Girolamo Muziano (1528-1592) by Cornelis Cort (circa 1533-1578), 1574-75 (Folder 18)
  - [034] [Annunciation] after Titian (circa 1488-1576), by Cornelis Cort (circa 1533-1578), undated (Folder 4)
  - [035] "The Triumph of the Trinity," after Titian (circa 1488-1576), by Cornelis Cort (circa 1533-1578), after 1566 (Folder 18)
  - [036] "Giovanni Contarini," after Giovanni Contarini (1549-circa 1604), drawn by Luigo Pompignoli, engraved by Antonio Costa (1804-1875), undated (Folder 4)
  - [037] [Musicians] after Giorgione (circa 1477-1510), drawn by Francesco Petrucci (1660-1719), engraved by T. ver Cruys, undated (Folder 4)
  - [038] [Cattle] after Aelbert Cuyp (1620-1691), undated (Folder 4)
  - [039] [Travelers by a riverside] after Philips Wouwerman (1619-1668), by Justus Danckerts, undated (Folder 4)
  - [040] "Vision of the Archbishop of Rouen," after C. A. Vaniloo by P. Druet, undated (Folder 4)
  - [041] [Woman with angels] after Correggio (1489-1534), by Gidu Change, undated (Folder 4)
  - [042] [Unidentified print] by Albrecht Durer (1471-1528), [undated] (Folder 4)
    Separated Materials
    Missing as of 1988.
  - [043] [Great Cardinal] by Albrecht Durer (1471-1528), before 1528 (Folder 17)
  - [044] [Man on horse slaying dragon] by Albrecht Durer (1471-1528), undated (Folder 4)
  - [045] "Madonna con bambino e S. Giovanni," after Guido Reni (1575-1642), drawn by Giovanni Sanguinetti (1789-1867), engraved by E. Errani, undated (Folder 16)
  - [046] "Canal of Dort," after Aelbert Cuyp (1620-1691), by James Fittler (1758-1835), 1808 (Folder 17)
  - [047] "Erasmo Gattamelata," after Giorgione (circa 1477-1510), drawn by Achille Farina (1804-1879), engraved by Giovanni Fosella, undated (Folder 5)
  - [048] "Madonna con bambino e S. Giovanni," after Annibale Carracci (1560-1609), drawn by G. Marrubini, engraved by Giovanni Fosella, undated (Folder 5)
  - [049] "Moses Striking the Rock," by Battista Franco (circa 1498-1561), undated (Folder 13)
  - [050] "Returning from the Chase," after Philips Wouwerman (1619-1668), by William French (circa 1815-1898), undated (Folder 16)
  - [051] "Cav. Leandro da Ponte, di Bassano," after Leandro Bassano (1557-1622), drawn by Emilio Lapi (circa 1815-circa 1890), engraved by Giuseppe Fusinati (1803-?), undated (Folder 5)
  - [052] [Portrait of man with ruff] after Anthony Van Dyck (1599-1641), by Cornelis Galle II (1615-1678), undated (Folder 5)
  - [053] "Philippus Melancthon," after Lucas Cranach (1472-1553), by Louis Joseph Ghemar (1820-1873), undated (Folder 5)
  - [054] "Sancta Anna," by Giordano Luca (1632-1705), undated (Folder 5)
  - [055] "Elisabeth d'Yorck," after Adriaen van der Werff (1659-1722), by Pieter Stevens van Gunst (1659-circa 1724), undated (Folder 5)
  - [056] [Biblical scene] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Christoffel Jegher (1596-circa 1652), undated (Folder 16)
  - [057] [Men seducing women] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Christoffel Jegher (1596-circa 1652), undated (Folder 13)
  - [058] [Women and musicians] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Christoffel Jegher (1596-circa 1652), undated (Folder 13)
  - [059] "Philip IV of Spain," by Pieter de Jode I (1570-1634), undated (Folder 16)
  - [060] "D. Ionnes de Montfert", after Anthony Van Dyck (1599-1641), by Pieter de Jode I (1570-1634), undated (Folder 5)
  - [061] [Procession] after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721), by Francois Joullain (1697-1778), undated (Folder 5)
  - [062] "Christ preaching," after Lambert Lombard (1506-1566), by Karolus, after 1537-39 (Folder 17)
  - [063] "Jane Seymour," published by T. & P. Knapton, 1746 (Folder 5)
  - [064] "Le Printemps," after Nicolas Lancret (1690-1743), by Benoit Audran (1661-1721), undated (Folder 6)
  - [065] "L'Hiver," after Nicolas Lancret (1690-1743), by Jacques Philippe Le Bas (1707-1783), undated (Folder 16)
  - [066] "L'Este," after Nicolas Lancret (1690-1743), by Gerard Jean-Baptiste Scotin (1671-1716), undated (Folder 6)
  - [067] "L'Autonne," after Nicolas Lancret (1690-1743), by Nicolas Henru Tardieu (1674-1749), undated (Folder 6)
  - [068] "Fra Llelio Blancatcio Commendat," after Anthony Van Dyck (1599-1641), by Nicola Lauwers, undated (Folder 6)
  - [069] "Interno di Chiesa," after Peeter Neefs (circa 1578-circa 1656), drawn by Donato Cellesi, engraved by Nicolas Auguste Leisnier (1787-1857), undated (Folder 6)
  - [070] [Mary and Jesus] after Elisabetta Sirani (1638-1665), by Lorenzo Lali (1612-1691), undated (Folder 6)
  - [071] "Margarita de Carlile Comitissa," after Anthony Van Dyck (1599-1641), by Pierre Lombard (1612-1682), undated (Folder 6)
  - [072] "Philippus Comes Pembrokiae," after Anthony Van Dyck (1599-1641), by Pierre Lombard (1612-1682), undated (Folder 6)
  - [073] "Madonna con Bambino e S. Caterina," after Titian (1488-1576), drawn by Angiolo Tricca (1817-1884), engraved by Pietro Mancion (1803-1888), undated (Folder 6)
  - [074] [Carrying Christ to tomb] after Andrea Mantegna (circa 1431-1506), undated (Folder 6)
  - [075] "S. Famiglia," after Annibale Carracci (1560-1609), drawn by Emilio Lapi (circa 1815-circa 1890?), engraved by A. Marchi, undated (Folder 7)
  - [076] "Pietro Paolo Rubens," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), drawn by L. C. Castelnovo, engraved by A. Marchi, undated (Folder 7)
  - [077] "L'Asomption de la Sainte Vierge," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Michel Demarne, undated (Folder 13)
  - [078] "Lodovico Caracci," after Lodovico Caracci (1555-1619), drawn by G. Marrubini, engraved by Guiseppe Marri (1788-1852), undated (Folder 7)
  - [079] "Ritratto D'Ignoto," after Hans Holbein the Younger (1497-1543), drawn by Giovanni Sanguinetti (1789-1867), engraved by Guiseppe Marri (1788-1852), undated (Folder 7)
  - [080] "Charity," after Jean-Baptiste Greuze (1725-1805), by Jean Massard (1740-1822), 1772 (Folder 16)
  - [081] "Le Duc D-Yorck," after Anthony Van Dyck (1599-1641), drawn by Dirk Van Bergen (circa 1645-circa 1690), engraved by Mige, undated (Folder 7)
  - [082] "S. Paulus," after Phillippe de Champaigne (1602-1674), by Jean Morin (1600-1650), undated (Folder 14)
  - [083] "S. Petrus," after Phillippe de Champaigne (1602-1674), by Jean Morin (1600-1650), undated (Folder 14)
  - [084] [Picnic] after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721) by Jean Moyreau (1690-1762), undated (Folder 7)
  - [085] "Le Frileaux," after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721), by Jean Moyreau (1690-1762), undated (Folder 7)
  - [086] "Le vin de L'etrier," after Philips Wouwerman (1619-1668), by Jean Moyreau (1690-1762), 1739 (Folder 16)
  - [087] "La Fontaine de Neptune," after Philips Wouwerman (1619-1668), by Jean Moyreau (1690-1762), 1748 (Folder 16)
  - [088] "La Buvette des Dames," after Philips Wouwerman (1619-1668), by Jean Moyreau (1690-1762), 1749 (Folder 14)
  - [089] "L'Arrive des Chasseurs," after Philips Wouwerman (1619-1668), by Jean Moyreau (1690-1762), 1735 (Folder 14)
  - [090] "Jean Francois Sarrasin," by Robert Nantueil (1623-1678), 1656 (Folder 7)
  - [091] "I Robusti, Do. Il Tintoretto," after Jacopo Tintoretto (1519-1594), drawn by I. Pomignoli, engraved by Girolama Nardini (1804-1867), undated (Folder 7)
  - [092] "Giulio Romano," after Giulio Romano (circa 1499-1546), drawn by I. C. Castelnuovo, engraved by E. Pascah, undated (Folder 7)
  - [093] "Vases, Lampes et Cassolettes," by Parcier et Fontaine, undated (Folder 8)
  - [094] [Portrait of man] after Titian (circa 1488-1576), drawn by Francesco Petrucci (1660-1719), engraved by Giovanni Domenico Picchianti (circa 1670-?), undated (Folder 8)
  - [095] "Bust of Antonius Canova"after Antonio d'Este (1754-1837), by Tommaso Piroli (1752-1824), 1796 (Folder 17)
  - [096] [Poor family outside of house] after Egbert van der Poel (1621-1664), by E. Plin (working 1780-1790), undated (Folder 8)
  - [097] [People frolicking] after Titian (circa 1488-1576), by Gio. Giacomo Rossi le Stama, undated (Folder 8)
  - [098] [Cherubs] after Titian (circa 1488-1576), by Gio. Giacomo Rossi le Stama, 1636 (Folder 8)
  - [099] "Adoration des Bergers," after Carlo Maratti (1625-1713), by Nicolas Jean-Baptiste de Poilly (1712-after 1758), undated (Folder 16)
  - [100] "La Voluptueuse," after Francois Boucher (1703-1770), by Policnith, undated (Folder 8)
  - [101] [Joseph] after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), by Paulus Pontius (1603-1658), undated (Folder 8)
  - [102] "D. Henricus Comes vanden Burghe," after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), by Paulus Pontius (1603-1658), undated (Folder 8)
  - [103] [Angels above group of mortals] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Francois Ragot (1638-1670), undated (Folder 14)
  - [104] "Lazare Veni Foras," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Francois Ragot (1638-1670), undated (Folder 14)
  - [105] [Christ on steps with followers] by Marcantonio Raimondi (circa 1480-circa 1534), undated (Folder 8)
  - [106] [Adam and Eve expelled from Eden] after Alberto, by Marcantonio Raimondi (circa 1480-circa 1534), undated (Folder 8)
  - [107] "Cattedrael d'anversa," after Peeter Neefs (circa 1578-circa 1656), drawn by Donato Cellesi, engraved by Charles Rolls, undated (Folder 9)
  - [108] [Old woman and child with candles] by Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), undated (Folder 9)
  - [109] [Christ laid in tomb] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Nicolaes Ryckmans (circa 1595-?), undated (Folder 9)
  - [110] [Annunciation] after Jacopo Tintoretto (1519-1594), by Egidius Sadeler II (1570-1629), undated (Folder 9)
  - [111] "Iacopo Palma Il Giovane," after Palma Il Giovane (1548-1628), drawn by A. Becheroni, engraved by Emilio Salvi, undated (Folder 9)
  - [112] "Albert Rubens," after a drawing by Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Luigi Schiavonetti (1765-1810), undated (Folder 9)
  - [113] [King Ferdinand] by Jacobus van Schoor, undated (Folder 9)
  - [114] [?] (Folder 9)
    Not in folder, May 2002.
  - [115, copy 1] "Portrait of Charles I," after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), by William Sharp (1749-1824), 1817 (Folder 14)
    Related Materials
    See also number 144.
  - [115, copy 2] "Portrait of Charles I," after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), by William Sharp (1749-1824), 1817 (Folder 18)
  - [116] [Christ wearing crown of thorns and carrying cross], undated (Folder 9)
  - [117] "Jugement de Paris," after Pierre Louis Surugue (1710-1772), by Hendrick Goltzius (1558-1617), undated (Folder 9)
  - [118] [Landscape with angels] after Herman van Swanevelt (1600-1665), undated (Folder 9)
  - [119] [Pope addressing man in bed] by Isaac Taylor (1730-1807), undated (Folder 10)
  - [120] [Woman with cherubs in garden] after Pietro Testa (1611-1650), by Gio. Giacoma Rossi, undated (Folder 10)
  - [121] [Heaven and Earth] after Pietro Testa (1611-1650), by Gio. Giacoma Rossi, undated (Folder 10)
  - [122] "Interno di Tempio Gotico,"after Peeter Neefs (circa 1578-circa 1656), drawn by Donato Cellesi, engraved by Isaiah Thomas (1749-1831), undated (Folder 10)
  - [123] "Holbeen," after Hans Holbein (1460-1524), drawn by A. Nirra, engraved by Paolo Toschi (1788-1854), undated (Folder 10)
  - [124] [Mary and Jesus] after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), undated (Folder 10)
  - [125] "Erasmus Rotterdamus," by Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), undated (Folder 10)
  - [126] "Anna Boleyn," after Hans Holbein (1460-1524), drawn by Joseph Vollinger (1790-1846), by J. Velten, undated (Folder 10)
  - [127] "Catherine of Aragon," after Adriaen van der Werff (1659-1722), by Cornelis Vermeulen (1644-1709), [1697] (Folder 17)
  - [128] "Anne de Cleves," after Adriaen van der Werff (1659-1722), by Cornelis Vermeulen (1644-1709), [1697] (Folder 10)
  - [129] "Jane Seymour," after Adriaen van der Werff (1659-1722), by Cornelis Vermeulen (1644-1709), [1697] (Folder 17)
  - [130] [People, some imprisoned] by Enea Vico (1523-1567), undated (Folder 10)
  - [131] [Poverty] after Adriaen van Ostade (1610-1685), drawn by Nicolas Visscher (1618-1709), engraved by Cornelis de Visser, undated (Folder 11)
  - [132] "The Morning," after Aelbert Cuyp (1620-1691), by Francois Vivares (1708-1780), 1754 (Folder 11)
  - [133] "The Evening," after Aelbert Cuyp (1620-1691), by Francois Vivares (1708-1780), 1760 (Folder 11)
  - [134] [Holy Family] after Raphael (1483-1520), by Andrea Valario, undated (Folder 11)
  - [135] "Francis of Assisi receiving the Stigmata," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Lucas Emil Vorsterman (1595-1675), undated (Folder 11)
  - [136] "Petrus Stevens," after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), by Lucas Emil Vorsterman (1595-1675), undated (Folder 11)
  - [137] [Moneylender] after Hans Holbein (1460-1524), drawn by John Boydell (1719-1804), engraved by Anthony Walker (1726-1765), undated (Folder 14)
  - [138] [Jesus carried into the tomb] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), by Jan Witdoeck (circa 1615- after 1642), undated (Folder 11)
  - [139] "La Bal Champetre," after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721), by William Henry Worthington (circa 1819-1839), undated (Folder 11)
  - [140] [Battle scene] after Guido Reni (1575-1642), by Borcho, undated (Folder 11)
  - [141] "Vade ad Mare," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640), undated (Folder 11)
  - [142] [Men at table with books] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577-1640) by Giusto Lipsio, undated (Folder 12)
  - [143] "La Baraque," after Salomon van Ruysdael (circa 1600-1670), undated (Folder 12)
  - [144] "Portrait of Charles I," after Anthony van Dyck (1599-1641), by William Sharp (1749-1824), 1817 (Folder 12)
    See also number 115.
  - [145] "Les Delassements de la Guerre," after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721), undated (Folder 12)
  - [146] "Les Fatigues de la Guerre," after Jean-Antoine Watteau (1684-1721), undated (Folder 12)
  - [147] [Christ on throne] after Gio. de Rossi, by Horatius Pacificus (working 1625), undated (Folder 12)